Finding Aid for Dewey Ames Papers, 1982-1998
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Dewey Ames Papers 1992-1998
Ames, Dewey.
1 linear foot and 1 oversize folder
2010224 Aa 2; UAl
Papers of Dewey Ames, a resident of the Metro Detroit Area who participated and organized athletic events, organizations, including the Gay Games. The collection is divided into two series Personal Records, and Other Materials.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers came to the library from Dewey Ames (donor no. 10432 )in 2010.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Dewey Ames was a Michigan native, residing in the Detroit Metro Area. As an active member of the gay community, Ames joined and organized the Detroit team, and later Team Great Lakes, which both participated in the Gay Games. The games began in 1982 as a cultural event for the purpose of unity and identity within the national and international gay and lesbian community. Ames was also involved in charity and fundraising events supporting a local AIDS organization.
The collection largely documents Dewey Ames involvement in the Gay Games throughout the 1980's and 1990's. The emphasis of these sporting events was to help the Gay and Lesbian Community establish a global unity and strengthen their identity. The Papers of Dewey Ames are arranged into two series, Personal Records, and Other Materials.
Subjects:
Ames, Dewey.; Gays and sports.; Gay Games.; Track and field--United States.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Posters.; Videotapes.
- Personal Records
  The Personal Records series documents Ames' involvement in the Gay Games, as well as the organizing of Team Great Lakes, in which he participated. Other items are related to his personal life and interest in Gay issues and culture.
  - Athletic Event Participation (Box 1)
  - Biographical (Box 1)
  - Charity and Fundraising (Box 1)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Policy (Box 1)
  - Gay Games I, San Francisco 1982 (Box 1)
  - Gay Games II, San Francisco, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Gay Games III, Vancouver, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Gay Games IV, New York, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Gay Games V, Amsterdam, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Newspapers, Clippings, and Magazines (Box 1)
  - Pride Guides and Festivals (Box 1)
  - Social Organizations and Other Events (Box 1)
  - Stone Riots 25th Anniversary Events (Box 1)
  - Team Great Lakes 1992-1998 Newsletters, 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Travel and Accommodation (Box 1)
- Other Materials
  The Other Materials series contains pictures of Team Great Lakes, Gay Games IV, and of the 25th Anniversary of Stonewall March in New York. Negatives are included with each set of the photos in a separate envelope. Ephemera included are pins, identification cards, and similar items from the Gay Games and other events. There is also one short video which includes Ames as an interviewee about the Gay Games and their significance.
  - Photographs
    - Team Great Lakes, Gay Games IV, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 25th Anniversary of the Stonewall Riots March, New York, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Ephemera
    - Pins, identification cards, banner, and similar items from the Gay Games and other events (Box 1)
  - Videotape
    - Promotional video entitled "Spirit of the Games" 1993, 1 VHS tape; ca. 5 min (Box 1)
  - Posters
    - Announcements from the Gay Games, 1982-1994, 6 posters (Folder 1)
      (the poster from 1982 is autographed by the design artist Geoffrey Graham)